

Institute of Automation · Chinese Academy of Sciences · Chin

95 Zhongguancun East Road, 100190, Beijing, China

□ (+86) 136-6738-3799 | ■ gongchen2020@ia.ac.cn | 😭 2019chengong.github.io | 📂 Chen Gong

Education

CUGB (China University Of Geosciences, Beijing)

Beijing, China

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY

Sep. 2016 - Jun. 2020

- GPA: 3.85/4.0
- Average score: 93.4/100.0
- Rank: 1/68
- Main courses: Higher Mathematics; College Physics; C++ Programming; Mathematics Modeling; Microcomputer Principle and Assembly Language; Discrete Mathematics and Formal Language; Linear Algebra; Programming Practices in Java; Data Structures; Computer Networks; Probability and Statistics; Object-Oriented Software Design; Computer Organization and Architecture; Algorithm Design and Analysis; Computer Graphics; Applications of Database Systems; Computer Network

CASIA (Institute of Automation, Chinese Academy of Sciences)

Beijing, China

M.S. IN PATTERN RECOGNITION AND INTELLIGENT SYSTEM

Jun. 2020 - Now

- GPA: 3.89/4.0
- Average score: 90.2/100.0
- Supervisor: Xinwen HOU, Yu LIU
- Main courses: Stochastic Processes; Pattern Recognition; Principle and Algorithms of Artificial Intelligence; Reinforcement Learning; Convex Analysis

Research Overview

My primary research interests include machine learning, reinforcement learning (RL), optimization, etc. Recently, my projects have focused on RL safety [1, 2], generative adversarial network [3], developing theories on RL optimization [3, 4, 5, 6, 7], and machine learning in EEG signals [8, 9, 10].

Research Experiences _____

School of Computing and Information Systems, Singapore Management University

Singapore

ADVERSARIAL POLICY LEARNING & REINFORCEMENT LEARNING SAFETY

Oct. 2021 - Now

- Supervisor: David LO
- Under black-box settings, we proposed effective adversarial policies using a curiosity-driven and victim-aware RL-based method to attack agents in a two-player game. Our attack approach exploited the vulnerability of victims efficiently.
- In offline RL, the agents learn from a pre-selected and fixed dataset. We poisoned the offline dataset to insert a backdoor to the agent. We hoped that the agent normally performed if and only if it suffered from performance degradation fastly when the trigger was presented.
- One paper was accepted by ACSAC 2022 [2]; One paper was submitted to IEEE Transaction on Software Engineering [1]
- Key words: Adversarial policy; Backdoor attack; Data poisoning; Offline reinforcement learning

Institute of Automation, Chinese Academy of Sciences

Beijing, China

 $f ext{-}\mathsf{Divergence}$ Reinforcement Learning

Feb. 2021 - Oct. 2021

- Supervisor: Xinwen HOU
- We developed a novel DRL framework: the policy evaluation and policy improvement phases were simultaneously performed by minimizing
 the f-divergence between the learning policy and sampling policy, which was distinct from conventional DRL algorithms aiming to maximize
 the expected cumulative results rewards.
- One paper was submitted to UAI 2022 [4].
- ullet Key words: Reinforcement learning; f-divergence; Fenchel conjugate

Institute of Automation, Chinese Academy of Sciences

Beijing, China

REINFORCEMENT LEARNING & VARIATIONAL INFERENCE

& Variational Inference Nov. 2019 - Dec .2020

- Supervisor: Xinwen HOU
- We developed variational-based methods to stabilize the reinforcement learning training process through the constraint of the Bellman residual distribution between two adjacent time steps.
- Two papers were accepted as oral in ICONIP 2020 [8] and ICME 2021 [7], respectively; I completed the undergraduate thesis that was awarded the "Excellent Graduation Thesis".
- · Key words: Bellman residual distribution; Stationary random process; Stein variational gradient descent; Quantile regression

Tsinghua University, School of Medicine

Beijing, China

MEDICAL IMAGE PROCESSING

Jul. 2019 - Aug. 2019

- Utilizing the Mask R-CNN algorithm, we segmented the coronary arteries of the heart in CTA images. We found that the appropriate image pre-processing and post-processing approach for CTA images would benefit the segmentation accuracy.
- · Key words: Mask R-CNN, Image segmentation; Coronary arteries

October 12, 2022 Byungjin Park · Résumé

MACHINE LEARNING IN MEDICINE

Dec. 2017 - Feb. 2019

- · Supervisor: Yunyun NIU
- We designed the model that combined machine learning and feature extraction methods to classify intracranial EEG signals for the automatic diagnosis of epilepsy diseases.
- Three papers were accepted by Applied Intelligence [9], Chinese Journal of Electronics [10], Computational Biology and Chemistry [11].
- Key Words: Intracranial Electroencephalogram (iEEG), Epilepsy; Discrete wavelet transform, Parallel computing, Local simulated annealing, Probabilistic neural network

Publications

[1] **Chen Gong**, Zhou Yang, Yunpeng Bai, Junda He, Jieke Shi, Arunesh Sinha, Xinwen Hou, Guoliang Fan, David Lo. Mind Your Data! Hiding Backdoor in Offline Reinforcement Learning Datasets. **Submitted** to IEEE Transaction on Software Engineering (TSE). [Paper][Code]

[2] **Chen Gong**, Zhou Yang, Yunpeng Bai, Jieke Shi, David Lo, Xinwen Hou, Arunesh Sinha, Bowen Xu, Guoliang Fan. Curiosity-Driven and Victim-Aware Adversarial Policies. **Accepted** by Annual Computer Security Applications Conference (ACSAC) 2022. (Technical Track, 15 pages.) [Paper] [Code]

[3] Siyu Xing, **Chen Gong**, Hewei Guo, Xiaoyu Zhang, Xinwen Hou, Yu Liu. Unsupervised Domain Adaptation GAN Inversion for Image Editing. **Submitted** to the Thirty-Seventh AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI) 2023.

[4] **Chen Gong***, Qiang He*, Yunpeng Bai*, Zhou Yang, Xiaoyu Chen, Xinwen Hou, Xianjie Zhang, Yu Liu, Guoliang Fan. The f-Divergence Reinforcement Learning Framework. **Submitted** to Conference on Uncertainty in Artificial Intelligence (UAI) 2022. [Paper]

[5] Qiang He, Huangyuan Su, **Chen Gong**, Xinwen Hou. MEPG: A Minimalist Ensemble Policy Gradient Framework for Deep Reinforcement Learning. **Accepted** by Decision Awareness in Reinforcement Learning Workshop at ICML 2022. [Paper]

[6] Yunpeng Bai*, **Chen Gong***, Bin Zhang*, Guoliang Fan, Xinwen Hou, Yu Liu. Cooperative Multi-Agent Reinforcement Learning with Hypergraph Convolution. **Accepted** by International Joint Conference on Neural Network (IJCNN) 2022. (oral, 9 pages.) [Paper] [Code]

[7] **Chen Gong***, Qiang He*, Yunpeng Bai, Xinwen Hou, Guoliang Fan, Yu Liu. Wide-Sense Stationary Policy Optimization with Bellman Residual on Video Games[C]. 2021 IEEE International Conference on Multimedia and Expo (ICME). IEEE, 2021: 1-6. **Published**. (oral, 6 pages.) [Paper]

[8] **Chen Gong**, Yunpeng Bai, Xinwen Hou, Xiaohui Ji. Stable Training of Bellman Error in Reinforcement Learning [C]. International Conference on Neural Information Processing. Springer, Cham, 2020:439-448. **Published**. (oral, 10 pages.) [Paper]

[9] **Chen Gong**, Xinchen Zhou, Yunyun Niu. Pattern recognition of epilepsy using parallel probabilistic neural network[J]. Applied Intelligence, 2021: 1-12. **Published**. (IF=5.09, 12 pages.) [Paper]

[10] **Chen Gong**, Jiahui Liu, Yunyun Niu. Intracranial Epileptic Seizures Detection Based on an Optimized Neural Network Classifier[J]. Chinese Journal of Electronics, 2021, 30(3): 419-425. **Published**. (IF=1.01, 7 pages.) [Paper]

[11] **Chen Gong**, Xiaoxiong Zhang, Yunun Niu. Identification of epilepsy from intracranial EEG signals by using different neural network models[J]. Computational Biology and Chemistry, 2020, 87: 107310. **Published**. (IF=3.73, 10 pages.) [Paper]

Awards & Honors

AWARDS

2020	Finalist, the COMAP's Mathematical Contest in Modeling	Beijing, China
2019	Meritorious Winner, the COMAP's Mathematical Contest in Modeling	Beijing, China
2018	Honorable Mention, the COMAP's Mathematical Contest in Modeling	Beijing, China
2018	First prize in Beijing, Contemporary Undergraduate Mathematical Contest in Modeling	Beijing, China
2017	First prize, Mathematics Competition of China University of Geosciences	Beijing, China
2015	First prize, Hunan High School Mathematics Competition	Hunan, China

HONORS

2021	Merit Student, University of Chinese Academy of Sciences	Beijing, China
2020	Beijing Outstanding Graduates, Beijing Municipal Education Commission	Beijing, China
2020	School-level Excellent Graduation Thesis, China University Of Geosciences, Beijing	Beijing, China
2017	Outstanding Member, China University Of Geosciences, Beijing	Beijing, China
2017	National Scholarship for Undergraduates, Ministry of Education of the people's Republic of China	Beijing, China

Skills, Certifications & Others

Languages: Chinese (Native) & English (CET6)

Skills: Python | C++ | Matlab | Linux | LaTex

Activities: Sharing my research notes in Zhihu website. Welcome to visit my Zhihu homepage: [Chen Gong's homepage].